英会話タイムトライアル
Let's get started with the first day of our special week.
It's day 16 for the month of September.
Hi, everyone. I'm Steve Sarese.
And I'm Jenny Skidmore. Thanks for joining us.
今月はさらに1週間特別なトレーニングをします。
Special week.
この1週間で英語の瞬発力をさらにアップさせていきましょう。
ということで、今日から2日間はこのトレーニングです。
SPR-robics!
次々と繰り出される日本語をリズムに乗って、
即座に英語で表現していくトレーニングです。
So let's have some fun building your SPR!
今月は衣類をテーマに学習しています。
ということで、今回のSPR-robicsでは、
出かけする2人の着替えにまつわる会話のやりとりを英語で表現しましょう。
さあ、お手本として僕とジェニーさんでいくつかのやりとりをやってみます。
今日のSPR Rubik'sはこんな感じです。
出かける準備はできた?
Are you ready to go?
まだ。
Not yet.
着替えた?
Did you change?
Did you understand how to practice?
You don't have time to think about it.
Try to express Japanese in English at a good tempo with the speed of the moment.
Then, let's get started.
Let's get started.
Are you ready to go out?
Not yet.
Did you change?
No, not yet.
急いで着替えて 今何時 もう行く時間だよ 今着替えるから 何を着るの まだ考え中 ほらこれを着て
これ、きれい?
洗濯したばっかりだよ。
縮んだ?
縮んでないよ。
きつく感じる。
かっこいいよ。
きつすぎない?
鏡を見て。
Ah, it's all right.
Don't forget one more thing.
Ah, I know.
Put the dirty clothes in here.
Roger that.
Completed.
Now, let's go out.
Okay, good job. How was your first round?
一回目はすべてできなくても大丈夫です。
ここでジェニーさんに挑戦してもらいます。
それぞれ英語でどのように表現するのかチェックしてみてください。
余裕のある方はジェニーさんと一緒に英語で言ってみてください。
So now it's your turn, Jenny. Are you ready?
Yeah, I'm ready, Steve.
Okay, let's hit the music. Here we go.
出かける準備はできた?
Are you ready to go?
まだ
Not yet
着替えた?
Did you change?
や、まだ
No, not yet
急いで着替えて
Hurry up and change
今何時?
What time is it now?
もう行く時間だよ
It's time to go
今着替えるから。
I'll change now.
何を着るの?
What are you wearing?
まだ考え中。
I'm still thinking about it.
ほら、これを着て。
Here, wear this.
これ、きれい?
Is this clean?
洗濯したばっかりだよ。
I just washed it.
縮んだ?
Did it shrink?
縮んでないよ。
It didn't shrink.
キツく感じる。
It feels tight.
かっこいいよ。
It looks good.
キツすぎない?
It's not too tight?
鏡を見て。
Look in the mirror.
あ、大丈夫だね。
Oh, it's fine.
Don't forget one more thing.
Oh, I know.
Dirty clothes go here.
Got it. Done. Okay, let's go.
Okay, did you understand how to express those phrases?
まず出だしの方をスムーズに言えるようにそれぞれチェックします。
出かける準備はできた?っていうのは
Are you ready? もしくは Are you ready to go?
その次は まだ
Not yet.
そして 着替えた?っていうのは
Did you change?
Did you change your clothes?は言わなくても簡単に
その他チェンジの入った表現もありましたね。
急いで着替えてっていうのは
Hurry up and change.
短く言えますね。
そして、今着替えるからっていうのは、
I'll change now.
I will change nowでもOKです。
また、以前一緒に練習した表現もありました。
まだ考え中っていうのは、
I'm still thinking.
そして、about it.
I'm still thinkingでも正解ですが、
よくabout itをつけます。
それではみなさん、このエスピアロビクスにもう一度チャレンジしましょう。
どれぐらい言えるかな?
OK, everyone. It's time for your second try. Let's go!
出かける準備はできた?
まだ。
着替えた?
いや、まだ。
Hurry up and change your clothes.
What time is it now?
It's time to go.
I'm going to change my clothes now.
What are you wearing?
I'm still thinking.
Here, wear this.
これ、きれい?
洗濯したばっかりだよ。
縮んだ?
縮んでないよ。
きつく感じる。
かっこいいよ。
きつすぎない?
鏡を見て。
Ah, it's okay.
Don't forget one more thing.
Ah, I know.
Put the dirty clothes in here.
Roger that.
Completed.
Now, let's go.
All right. Good job, everyone.
Were you able to say those phrases a little better than the first time around?
SPR Robics, it's your first day. Good job.
Each of them were short expressions, but you can say them instantly, so you don't have to practice.
Thanks for practicing.
And tomorrow, we have more SPR Robics.
Tomorrow, we will increase the speed of the sprint.
So everyone, get on board.
And let's practice speaking together.
See you next time on...
Ekaewa Time Trial.
Bye-bye.